Guide to the Percy Simpson Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Percy Simpson papers
1870-1953
OSB MSS 8
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
5
(15 boxes)
Correspondence, writings, scrapbooks and printed material documenting aspects of the scholarly career of Percy Simpson, particularly his edition of Ben Jonson's Works (1925-52) and his professional relationships with his colleagues, especially C. H. Herford, R. W. Chapman, William A. Jackson, Sir Humphrey Sumner Milford, and Eugénie Sellers Strong.
Simpson, Percy, 1865-1962
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For further information, please consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
CONTENTS OF BOXES
Box 1 -- 2 Scrapbooks, containing press cuttings, 1870-1953
5 Letters to Simpson Misc. Memorabilia from Awards of Honorary Degrees
Box 2 -- Notebooks 1-6
Box 3 -- Notebooks 7-14
Box 4 -- Folder 1 Off-prints of articles published by Simpson 1896-1953
-------- Folder 2 Off-prints of reviews by Simpson
-------- Folder 3 Off-prints of Simpson's colleagues
-------- Folder 4 Misc. printed matter
Box 5 -- Folder 1 Notes on proofreading and punctuation
-------- Folder 2 Notes, facsimiles, correspondence related to proofreading
-------- Folder 3 20th-Century theater programs
-------- Folder 4 "Monthly Letters" of William Poel
Box 6 -- Folder 1 Photostats for "paradoxes and problems"
-------- Folder 2 Photostats of Jonson texts
-------- Folder 3 Misc. photostats and facsimiles
-------- Folder 4 Notes on Jonson
-------- Folder 5 Notes for "Love's Martyr"
-------- Folder 6 Notes, correspondence relating to Jonson portraits
-------- Folder 7 Notes on Jonson's library
-------- Folder 8 Plates, proofs for "Masque of Queens"
-------- Folder 9 Notes on Lucy, Countess of Bedford
-------- Folder 10 Notes on Shakespeare plays
-------- Folder 11 Notes for "Shakespearean Punctuation"
-------- Folder 12 Typescript of "Shakespeare's Latin"
Box 7 -- Folder 1 Notes for teaching of Greek, 1883-84
-------- Folder 2 Lecture notes for course in Bibliography, 1913-19
-------- Folder 3 Notes, lecture notes on Matthew Arnold
-------- Folder 4 Personal items
-------- Folder 5 Bibliographical Society and Oxford Bibliographical Society materials, 1915-53
-------- Folder 6 Misc. notes by Simpson
-------- Folder 7 Notes on Chapman's Homer
-------- Folder 8 Notes on Huchon(?)
-------- Folder 9 Notes on Corpus Christi (Oxford) MS 325
-------- Folder 10 Notes on Phillips MS 9624 (Brodbent)
-------- Folder 11 Tutor play fragment (Wadham College, Oxford)
-------- Folder 12 Notes of Trinity College (Cambridge) MS B.14,22
-------- Folder 13 Notes on Cicero
-------- Folder 14 Materials from Oriel College (Oxford) Sexcentury, 1926
-------- Folder 15 Misc. typescripts
Boxes 8-10 -- Correspondence
Learning and scholarship -- Great Britain; Scholars -- Great Britain; Abraham, Charles John, 1814-1903; Bang, W. (Willy), 1869-1934; Chambers, E. K. (Edmund Kerchever), 1866-1954; Chapman, R. W. (Robert William), 1881-1960; Cockerell, Sydney Carlyle, Sir, 1867-1962; Drinkwater, John, 1882-1937; Garrod, H. W. (Heathcote William), 1878-1960; Greg, W. W. (Walter Wilson), 1875-1959; Herford, C. H. (Charles Harold), 1853-1931; Jackson, William A. (William Alexander), 1905-1964; Jenkinson, Hilary, Sir, 1882-1961; Jonson, Ben, 1573?-1637 -- Criticism and interpretation; Masefield, John, 1878-1967; Milford, Humphrey Sumner, Sir, 1877-1952; Raleigh, Walter, 1861-1922; Simpson, Percy, 1865-1962; Strong, Eugénie, 1860-1943; University of Oxford -- Faculty; University of Oxford -- Intellectual life
- Scrapbooks
  - Two large scrapbooks containing press cuttings from TLS, Notes and Queries, The Oxford Magazine, Athenaeum, Modern Language Quarterly, Modern Language Review, The London Times, Oxford University Gazette, Oriel College Record, The Denstonian, The Periodical, The Glasgow Herald, Radio Times. Most concern issues in Jonson scholarship, but several reviews by Simpson are included, 1870-1953. (Box 1)
  - The volumes also contain memorabilia from Awarding of Honorary Degrees from Cambridge and Glasgow Universities, 1951.
  - 5 Letters to Simpson are enclosed, as follows:
  - Fordyce, C.J.
    Scope and Contents
    LS to Percy Simpson
    1950 Jun 20, Glasgow
    1 p. 26 x 21 cm
    Notifies Simpson of Glasgow's academic senate's decision to confer on him Honorary Doctor of Law Degree
  - Jones, Philip E.
    ALS to Percy Simpson
    1953 Oct 24, London
    2 p. 21 x 13 cm
    Explains reference to "Great Gobletto" in Cyles
    Oldisworth's elegy to Ben Jonson (1637)
    [cf. TLS 1953 Nov 27]
  - Roberts, S.C.
    1951 Feb 13, Cambridge
    Inquires if Simpson will accept Honorary Degree of
    University
  - Spear, T.G. Percival
    1951 May 3, Cambridge
    1 p. 23 x 18 cm
    Arranges dinner with Master and Fellows
  - Telfer, W.
    1951 May 18, Cambridge
    2 p. 18 x 13 cm
    Asks Simpson to accept Honorary Fellowship of Selwyn
    College
  - Tillyard, E.M.W.
    1951 Apr 27, Cambridge
    Invites Simpson to stay at Jesus College
- Notebooks
  - 1. Translations of English writers into Greek prose (Box 2)
  - 2. Translations of English writers into Latin prose
  - 3. Translations of English writers into Greek verse
  - 4. Translations of English writers into Latin verse
  - 5. Notebook: sections of French translations of English prose; incomplete Greek-English Lexicon; misc. quotations and notes
  - 6. Notebook: "Lectures by Dr. Reid given at Pembroke College, May Term 1885; Selections from Pliny's Letters"
  - 7. Notebook: "Translations and Extracts from 'The Journal of Education' and other sources [i.e. Longman's Magazine ]. Contains notes and cuttings, 1889-93. (Box 3)
  - 8. Notes on Julius Caesar, Acts I-V
  - 9. Notes on MS pedigree and migrations for Chaucer texts and their sources, esp. Boccaccio.
  - 10. Notes on "The Vernon MS" (Bod. MS Engl. Poet. A1). Misc. notes on physical and textual aspects.
  - 11. Notes on Jonson's Batholomew Fair [contains misc. notes and press cuttings related to Bartholomew Fair ].
  - 12. Notes on MSS: Trinity College, Dublin MS G-2-21 [Donne poems and others]; "The Books of the Revells Ending the Last Day of October, An. Dom.: 1612;" Edinburgh University MS of Jonson's Poems, 1640
  - 13. Notebook: "Gur Magazine. Edited by Lady EMS. Saturday, March 13th, 1897." MS installments [not in Simpson's hand] run to Saturday, May 8th, 1897, a total of 62 pages.
- Correspondence
  - Abbot, Edwin A. (Box 8)
    1913 Jul 2, Hampstead
    2 p. 15 x 10 cm
    Thanks for Simpson's note on Shakespearean grammar
  - Abercrombie, Lascalles, 1881-1938
    1935 Jul 4, Stanley Gardens
    1 p. 18 x 11 cm
    Accepts appointment
    ? Mar 24, Oxford
    2 p. 18 x 11 cm
    Accepts presidency of English Association
  - Abraham, Charles John, 1814-1903
    1880 Jun 2, Lichfield
    3 p. 18 x 11 cm
    Congratulations on Simpson's successes in school and his
    decision to be confirmed
    1883 July, 20, Lichfield
    4 p. 18 x 11 cm
    Discusss Simpson's need for scholarship money to attend
    Selwyn College, Cambridge
    1884 Feb 18, N/P
    Encloses notice of scholarship at Selwyn College
    [wanting]
    1884? Lichfield
    Sends congratulations
    ALS frags
    5 p. 18 x 11 cm
    ALS to Mrs. Simpson
    1884 Jul 29, Lichfield
    Explains cost of Selwyn College
    1884 Aug 2, Lichfield
    Enclosed letter from Mrs. Selwyn in which she offers
    financial support to Percy [wanting]
  - Alexander, Peter, 1893-
    1945 Oct 30, Glasgow
    2 p. 13 x 21 cm
    Sends best wishes
    1947 May 31, Glasgow
    2 p. 21 x 31, cm
    Notes on Shakespearean punctuation
    1950 Feb 17, Glasgow
    4 p. 21 x 13 cm
    Queries Simpson about card games, promises to visit him
    1950 Feb 22, Glasgow
    Mentions argument on Shakespeare's career he plans to
    publish
    1952 Oct 22, Glasgow
    Says books were to have been sent to Simpson
    1952 Oct 31, Glasgow
    6 p. 21 x 13 cm
    Answers several of Simpson's criticisms of new book
    1955 Mar 25, Glasgow
    2 p. 18 x 12 cm
    Thanks Simpson for copy of his Studies 1947 Mar 25, Glasgow
    Discusses punctuation; with off-print
    "Shakespeare's Punctuation"
    1947 May 17, Glasgow
    9 p. 26 x 21 cm
    Notes and queries on "hen in the forehead" and others
    1947 May 23, Glasgow
    6 p. 26 x 21 cm
    Misc. textual notes
  - Allen, Percy Stafford, 1869-1933
    1932 Oct 9, Wimpole Street
    1 p. 18 x 12 cm
    Comments on letter of Erasmus, dated Feb. 1536
  - Anderson, A.
    1903 Dec 6, Edinburgh
    Promises that the University Library will assist him
  - Anderson, Joseph, 1832-1916
    1903 Dec 24, Edinburgh
    Reports the council of the Society of Antiquaries of
    Scotland voted to allow him access to Strawthornden MSS
  - Atkins, S.H.
    1935 Jun 16, Chester
    Inquires about Gamaliel Ratsey in The Alchemist 1935 June 21, Chester
    Encloses copy of Ratsey facsimile [wanting]
  - Ault, Norman, 1880-
    ALS to Percy Simpson Osborn pe 378
    1920 Oct 22, Oxford
    Presents copy of Dreamland Shores
  - Balkwill, Michael
    N/D, Gairaut, Nice A.M.
    2 p. 23 x 18 cm
    Thanks Simpson for 2 years of English instruction
  - Ballinger, Sir John, 1860-1933
    1928 Aug 20, Aberystwyth
    1 p. 21 x 26 cm
    Invites Simpson to use The National Library of Wales
    [enclosure wanting]
  - Bang, Willi
    1904 Oct 27, Lourain
    1 p. 14 x 9 cm
    Sends, at Herford's request, sheets A-V of 1616 Jonson
    folio
    1904 Nov 13, Lourain
    Reports sale of painting of Ben Jonson
    1904 Dec 14, Lourain
    Comments of 1640 printing of The Masque of Gypsies 1904 Dec 26 Lourain
    Refers to English Studien v. 34 heft 3 for pertinent
    review
    1905 Jan 11, Lourain
    Offers aid in Simpson's work on Jonson
    1905 Jan 14, Lourain
    3 p. 16 x 11 cm
    Misc comments on Jonson textual editing
    1906 Jan 26, Lourain
    Misc comments on Jonson; question about John Ford
    1925 Jun 29, Berlin
    Offers his congratulations to Simpson
    1925 Jul 4, Darmstadt
    2 p. 14 x 9 cm
    Thanks him for copy of off-print on Jonson
    1925 Aug 5, Darmstadt
    Best wishes for forthcoming volumes of Jonson
  - Bayfield, Matthew Albert, 1852- Osborn pe 404
    1922 May 25, Hartings Fordburg
    2 p. 26 x 21 cm
    Comments on Jonson and others
  - Beerbohm, Sir Max, 1872-1956
    1921 Oct 29, Villino Chiaro, Rapullo
    2 p. 17 x 12 cm
    Declines invitation to address English Association of
    Oxford
  - Bell, C.K.A.
    1925 May 26, Canterbury
    1 p. 20 x 25 cm
    Invites Simpson to come to Canterbury
  - Bell, Charles H.
    149 ALS to Percy Simpson
    1924-1955
  - Bennett, H. S.
    1945 Oct 31, Cambridge
    1 p. 9 x 12 cm
    Wishes Simpson happy returns
  - Bensly, Edward
    1928 Dec 14, Cardiganshire
    3 p. 18 x 12 cm
    Comments on song in Bartholomew Fair III, i
  - Binyon, Sir Laurence, 1869-1943
    1921 Nov 5, London
    1 p. 21 x 13 cm
    Cannot accept invitation to lecture
    1922 London
    1 p. 9 x 14 cm
    Is happy with date change for lecture
    1939 Feb 15, Strentley, Berkshire
    1 p. 11 x 18 cm
    Reports that his volume of Essays & Studies is printed
  - Bland, W.A.
    1904 May 11, Dublin
    4 p. 18 x 12 cm
    Supplies transcription [wanting] of T[rinity] C[ollege]
    MS
  - Blunden, Edmund, 1896-1974
    1931 Nov 17, Oxford
    1 p. 17 x 13 cm
    Must cancel his appointment with Simpson
    1933 Jan 25, Oxford
    2 p. 9 x 12 cm
    Accepts invitation for Feb 2
    1933 Oct 1, Oxford
    1 p. 24 x 17 cm
    Discusses Rhodes Scholar
    1939 May 11, Oxford
    Thanks him for Meyer's translations from Herbert
  - Bone, Sir Muirhead, 1876- Osborn pe 385
    1944 Jun 25, Oxford
    2 p. 12 x 9 cm
    Presents copy of Gavin Bone's Anglo Saxon Poetry
  - Bradley, Andrew Cecil, 1851-1935
    N/D, Kensington
    Discusses future meetings
    Asks Simpson's opinion on asking Bons to lecture
    Apr 2, Kensington
    Apr 26, Kensington
    [with enclosures]
    Jan 20, Kensington
    4 p. 16 x 10 cm
    3 p. 16 x 10 cm
    1913 Oct 13, Kensington
    Comments on his "Everyman"
    Nov 25, Kensington
    Sunday, Kensington
    Dec 8, Rensington
    Nov 6, Rensington
    1921 Apr 22, Kensington
    2 p. 16 x 10 cm
    Xmas Day, Kensington
    Asks Simpson to act as collector for next Essays and
    Studies volume
    May 28, Kensington
    Jun 1, Kensington
    Oct 16, Kensington
    [N.B. letters from Bradley appear as they stood Dec, 1981]
  - Bradley, Henry, 1845-1923
    AES to Percy Simpson
    1910 Apr 16, Oxford
    Wishes to resign his post on committee
    1919 Sep 24, Oxford
    Discusses derivation of "strummel-patcht"
    1919 Oct 20, Oxford
    1 p. 12 x 18 cm
    Comments on Every Man in His Humour 1919 Oct 22, Oxford
    1 p. 16 x 10 cm
    Comments on footnotes in Simpson's edition
    1923 Apr 16, Oxford
    Answers queries on certain words and phrases
  - Brettle, R. E.
    1928 Jun 11, Nottington
    Comments on Marston materials [MLR v XXII (Jan 1929)
    enclosed]
    1929 Jul 14, Surrey
    Theorizes on editions of Eastward Hoe 1929 July 29, Surrey
    Details of theory on Eastward Hoe
  - Brettsmith, H.F.B.
    1927 Jul 20, Oxford
    Asks to borrow Othello, Furness, ed.
  - Bridges, Robert Seymour, 1844-1930
    1911 Jan 2, Chilswell
    Asks that he not be called upon to speak at next meeting
    1911 Feb 12, Chilswell
    Thanks him for opportunity to speak at committee meeting
    discusses phonetic spelling
  - Bryson, J.W.
    1952 Nov 12, Oxford
    Discusses arrangements for portrait of Simpson
    1953 Mar 14, Oxford
    Asks that portrait drawing be allowed to be exhibited
  - Buchan, John, 1875-1940
    1922 Mar 7, Oxford
    Accepts presidency of Oxford branch of the English
    Association
  - Bucher, Hannah
    1940 Mar 1, Glasgow
    Encloses copy of Poems of the Pestell [wanting]
  - Bullen, Arthur Henry, 1857-1920 Osborn pe 401/3
    ALS to George Thorn-Drury
    1901 Mar 31, London (?)
    3 p. 12 x 18 cm
    Encloses sheets of "Beaumont & Fletcher"
  - Burgh, Alfred de
    AlS to Percy Simpson
    1904 Mar 30, Dublin
    2p. 23 x 18 cm
    Grants permission to examine and publish extracts from
    Trinity College MSS
  - Burney, Charles Fox, 1863-1925
    1903 Nov 6, Oxford
    1 p. 15 x 10 cm
    Agrees to show him St. John's College MSS
  - Burns, John
    1936 Jan 29, Ballersen
    1 p. 22 x 16 cm
    Agrees to show him copy of Jonson
    Poly-Olbion (1612)
  - Bury, John Bagnell, 1861-1927
    1924 Jan 7, Bath
    Agrees to investigate William Roe
  - Bywater, Ingram, 1840-1914
    1912 May 27, London (?)
    1 p. 16 x 11 cm
    Invites Simpson to lunch
  - Campbell, Oscar James, 1879-
    1939 Feb 4, New York
    1 p. 20 x 21 cm
    Encloses copy of his Comical Satyre and Shakespeare's "Troilus and Cressida" [separate cover]
  - Cannan, C.
    1903 July 14, Oxford
    Assures him that board will approve any decision made by
    both Simpson and Herford
    1904 May 30, Oxford
    Query on dating of The Tempest 1905 Mar 10, Oxford
    Discusses points of grammar; invites Simpson to Oxford
    1905 Mar 13, Oxford
    Invites Simpson to Oxford
    1905 Mar 15, Oxford
    Arranges meeting with Raleigh
    1905 Apr 5, Oxford
    Remarks on Simpson's scenes from Shakespeare
    1905 Sept 20, Oxford
    Asks for information on publishing date
  - Care, Robert Hope, 1857-
    1910 May 6, Liverpool
    1932 Feb 29, Liverpool
  - Castlelain, M.
    1909 May 22, Poitiers
    1919 Nov 17, Poitiers
    Thanks for copy of Every Man in His Humor that is to be
    sent to him
    1919 Dec 9, Poitiers
    Thanks for copy of Every Man in His Humor
  - Chambers, Sir Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954
    1910 Jan 2, Gerrard's Cross
    1930 Dec 8, Eynsham
    Thanks for compliments; reports finding an unpublished
    Donne elegy
    1931 May 10, Oxford
    Returns "Shakespearean Punctuation"
    1931 Dec 17, Eynsham
    Discusses plans for new scholarship in English
    1932 Apr 24, Eynsham
    Nominations for shadow poet
    1933 Jul 19, Eynsham
    Textual point in Faustus 1938 Jan 31, Oxford
    1939 Apr 5, Oxford
    Answers Simpson's query on Jonson's Christmas 1939 Aug 27, Devon
    Discusses Matthew Arnold copyrights and editions
    1940 Nov 10, Devon
    1 p. 18 x 13 cm
    Point on Matthew Arnold and A.C. Bradley
    1941 Jan 17, Devon
    Asks Simpson to check quotations in Bodley
  - Chambers, Raymond Wilson, 1874-
    N/D, London
    Offers congratulations
  - Chapman, Guy, 1887- Osborn pe 406
    1929 Jul 15, Whitby, Yorkshire
    Comments on Ben Jonson, Inigo Jones
    1929 Dec 10, Whitby, Yorkshire
    Comments on Masque of Queens 1930 Feb 4, Whitby, Yorkshire
    Comments on Masque of Queens
  - Chapman, Robert William, 1881-1960
    1923 Jul 13, Oxford
    Points in Shakespeare commentary
    1929 May 21, Oxford
    Comments on Article in BQR 1934 May 6, Oxford
    3 p. 26 x 21 cm
    1942 Feb 7, Oxford
    Reports his resignation as secretary
    1947 May 23, Sussex
    1951 Oct 12, Park Tan
    1 p. 25 x 16 cm
  - Charles, Robert Henry, 1855-
    ALS to Percy Simpsom
    1920 Sept 11, Westminster Abbey
    Writes on behalf of H.F. Westlake
  - Charlton, Henry Buckley, 1890-
    1945 Oct 30, Manchester
    Birthday wishes for Simpson's 80th birthday
  - Child, Harold Hannyngton, 1869-1945
    1941 Oct 2, London
    Asks permission to cite Simpson's name in Times collection.
  - Clark, Arthur Melville, 1895-
    1931 Jun 7, Edinburgh
    Comments on his book, Thomas Heywood Poet and Playwright
  - Cockerell, Sir Sidney Carlyle, 1867-1962
    1922 Oct 16, Cambridge
    Surmises on lines possibly written by Jonson
    1922 Nov 5, Cambridge
    Discusses Jonson's ownership copy
    1922 Dec 5, Cambridge
    Reports that Housman agrees with Simpson
    1923 Feb 21, Cambridge
    Grants permission to quote verses in question
    1923 Nov 23, Cambridge
    Reports purchase of Jonson ownership Aristophanes folio
    1923 Nov 30, Cambridge
    Query on Jonson volume
    1925 Jun 27, Cambridge
    Thanks Simpson for letter and chapter on Jonson
    1930 Mar 10, Cambridge
    Reports on Jonson's copy of Chapman's Homer
  - Coghill, Nevill, 1899-
    1945 Oct 31, Oxford
    ? Jun 23, Oxford
    Discusses dramatic productions
  - Cole, George Watson, 1850-1939
    1929 Feb 16, Pasadena, Calif.
    Notes on Jonson texts
    1929 July 22, Aldwych
  - Cooper, F.D.
    1946 Oct 1, London
    Affirms Simpson's quotation from Melville's "Princips:
    Scoti-Britannorum Natalia"
  - Craig, Edwin Stewart, 1865-
    1913 Jul 25, Oxford
    Invites Simpson to offer a course in textual criticism
    N/D, Oxford
    Offers Goldsmith's Readership in English to Simpson
    Reports recommendation of Vistatorial Board
  - Craigie, William Alexander, 1867-
    1930 Sep 5, Oxford
    Comments on readings of the Sad Shepherd 1947 Sep 22, Oxford
    Offers reading of unknown phrase in Pleasure Reconciled to Virtue.
    1950 May 6, Oxford
    Offers possible explanation for allusion to Abbots
  - Crarter, H.H.E.
    1934 Apr 3, Oxford
    Discusses Bodleian reading rooms
    1937 Oct 30, Oxford
    1 p. Z3 x 18 cm
    Thanks Simpson for his help in Jonson exhibition
  - Darbishire, Helen, 1861-
    1935 Jun 14, Oxford
    Thanks Simpson upon his retirement as Librarian
  - Dawson, Giles Edwin, 1903-
    1936 Jul 28, Washington
    4 p. 26 x 21 cm
    Information on Folger Jonsoniana
    1937 Nov 4, Washington
    Note on Jonson autograph
    1938 Jan 14, Washington
    Notes on Jonson autograph
    1940 Mar 22, Washington
    Notes on two Jonson autographs
    1941 June 21, Washington
    Notes on Jonson's copy of 1602 Chaucer
  - Davenport, A.
    1949 Nov 18, Wigan
    Theory on The Whipping and its authorship
  - Devonshire, Victor William Cavendish, Duke of, 1868-
    1938 Jul 7, London
    Grants permission to use Jonson's Pleasure Reconciled to Virtue
  - de la Mare, Walter John, 1873-1956
    1920 May 15, Anderley
    2 p. 12 x 18 cm
    Will accept invitation to lecture for English Association
    1920 May 19, Anderley
    Cannot accept Simpson's suggested dates
    1920 Sep 29, Anderley
    Suggests date and topic for lecture
    1920 Oct 14, Anderley
    Accepts invitation to tea
  - de L'Isle and Dudley, Philip Shelley - Sidney, 3rd Baron
    1947 July 21, Kent
    Gives readings on Jonson's poem on Penshurst
  - Dixey, Frederick Augustus, 1855-
    1923 Oct 24, Oxford
    Invites Simpson to join members of Wadham College Common
    Room
  - Dobell, Bertram, 1842-1914
    1904 Feb 10, London
    Discusses Jonson MS and its publication restrictions
    1904 Feb 12, London
    Discusses Trinity Col. MS.
    1904 Apr 5, London
    Reports that permission to use Jonson's letters in
    Chapman MS has been granted
    1904 Apr 22, London
    Thanks him for checking Strode MS in Dublin
    1904 Apr 24, London
    Extends use of Chapman MS transcription
    AL to Percy Simpson
    1904 Apr 27, London
    Reports on Strode research
    1906 Jan 17, London
    Comments on Strode
    1908 Apr, London
    Encloses transcription of "The Goodwifes Ale" [wanting]
  - Dobell, Percy John
    1922 Sep 15, London
    Extends use of Jonson pieces; offers aid in DNB notice
    on his father
    1925 Jul 9, London
    Thanks Simpson for presentation volumes; asks him about
    possible Donne MS section
  - Dobel, C.E.
    1903 Mar 26, Oxford
    Reports that Delegates of OUP are considering Jonson
    edition
    1903 Jun 18, Oxford
    Reports that C.H. Herford will accept Simpson's
    assistance on proposed Jonson edition
  - Drinkwater, John, 1882-1937
    1924 Mar 29, London
    1 p. 13 x 21 cm
    Questions Hartley Coleridge's appointments as Oriel
    Fellow
    1924 Apr 2, London
    Thanks Simpson for answer
    1924 Jul 3, London
    Accepts invitation to speak to English Assoc. at Oxford
    1924 Jul 10, London
    Is unsure of date for speaking engagement
    1924 Sep 24, London
    Has booked Nov. 7
    1924 Oct 3, London
    Asks about audience for speech on Nov. 7
    1924 Oct 9, London
    Suggests Byron's plays as a topic
    1924 Oct 13, London
    Accepts lunch invitation
    1924 Nov 6, London
    Arranges to meet Simpson at Oriel
  - Duff, Edward Gordon, 1863-1924
    1922 Aug 25, Oxford
    1 p. 15 x 11 cm
    Offers to let him see copy of 1640 Jonson Folio
  - Duke, E.
    1922 Jan 10, London
    Allows Simpson to examine documents of consistory court
    of London
  - Dunville, John
    ALS to ?
    1895 May 2, Piccadilly W.
    The Duke of Devonshire will allow Simpson access to
    documents he requests [enclosure]
  - Easton, Malcolm
    1932 Jul 26, Primrose Hill
    Thanks Simpson for his remarks
  - Edmonds, Cecil Kay
    1929 Jun 1, San Marino
    Summarizes Huntington copies of Jonson works
  - Ellesmere, Francis Charles Granville Egerton, 3rd Earl of
    1847-
    ALS to Mr. Hodgkisse
    1893 Dec 25, Worsley
    Restricts Simpson's use of his books
    1893 Dec 27, Worsley
    Regrets he cannot locate Jonson MS
    1909 Jun 28, London
    Has referred his query to Bridgewater Librarian
    1956 Jan 23, Roxburghshire
    1 p. 18 x 14 cm
    Will take portrait of 1st Earl of Bridgesater to National
    Gallery in Edinburgh
  - Elton, Oliver, 1861-
    1932 Mar 14, Oxford
    Accepts Presidency for term Oct 1932 - June 1933
    1935 Feb 1, Oxford
    Suggests Simpson look up "Reflections, by R.Q.," 1928
    1937 Mar 23, Oxford
    Offer congratulations on doctorate
    1941 Sept 21, Oxford
    Thanks Simpson for vol 7, Ben Jonson
    1943 Aug 13, Oxford
    1 p. 11 x 15 cm
    Asks who is to write DNB memoir for C.H. Herford
  - Ernest, A.
    ALS to Braunholtz
    1938 Nov 22, Oxford
    Comment on forms of Maison
  - Everett, E.M.
    1920 Sep 15, Dulwich College